showbie.com 2019-04-06

# Privacy – Showbie

The following is our Privacy Policy. It discusses the high degree of importance that we place on your privacy, including how we collect, use and disclose “Personal Information” as well as the rules and conditions related to privacy of information while using our service.

#### 1\. Our Privacy Pledge

Showbie Inc. (“ **Showbie** ”, “we” or “us”) provides certain services including our mobile application (the “ **Application** ”) and related software services as more particularly described in our Terms of Use (“ **Services** ”). We want you to know that your trust is key to the success of our business. We take privacy and confidentiality very seriously and we safeguard the personal information of our users in accordance with this Policy.

In this Policy Personal Information” means personal information about an identifiable individual and information which can be used to identify an individual.

Showbie complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of Personal Information. Please refer to Addendum 1.1 of this policy for more information regarding EU Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Certification.

For residents of the European Economic Area, Showbie generally processes Personal Information in order to fulfill contracts we have with our customers and Users and to pursue our legitimate business interests listed above. Otherwise, Showbie will obtain consent from a Data Subject in respect of processing of Personal Information if required by law to do so.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that we do not own or control. Our customers are responsible for maintaining their own privacy policies governing the collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information and are responsible for ensuring that they have obtained the necessary authorizations and consents for any Personal Information made available to us for use in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

#### 2\. Consent

By using our Services and supplying information to us, or by using the Showbie Application, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information by us for the purpose of providing Services to you via the Showbie Application, and administering your account in accordance with: (a) this Policy, (b) any other agreement you may have entered into with us, and (c) applicable laws and regulations. It is your responsibility to ensure that we are kept informed of the correct and current contact information for you.

#### 3\. Single Sign-On

You are able to log in to our Services using certain specified third-party accounts such as Google. We may add other third-party sign-on functionality from time to time. By signing on in this way, you consent to the use of certain information to authenticate your identity, and you consent to share certain Personal Information with us (such as name, profile picture (if available) and email address) to pre-populate your profile. We safeguard this information the same way as any Personal Information collected by us through the Services, as outlined in this Policy.

Some third-party services give you the option to post or share information about your use of the services to your third-party account. The settings for that kind of sharing are outside of our Services. It’s up to you to check the sharing and privacy settings on your third-party account.

#### 4\. Collection of User Information

Showbie collects limited Personal Information from administrative personnel at the school board, educational institution, school,  teachers or other organization that  has contracted with Showbie, only as needed for the operation and management of the Services provided by Showbie and as needed for account administration, including communicating with users and designated third-party service providers as required for account administration.

#### 5\. Collection of Student Information

(a) Showbie collects limited Personal Information from minor students, only as needed for the operation and management of the services provided by Showbie, and only where that student’s school board, educational institution or teacher has contracted with Showbie to do so. In particular, Showbie collects names, usernames, and profile pictures. This profile information collected allows students to interact with other teachers, students and other users from their school or institution as more particularly described below.

(b) **We first require the school board, educational institution or teacher to obtain the consent of parents/legal guardians prior to collecting such student Personal Information. If you are a minor student, do not upload or send any Personal Information about yourself or other students to Showbie, other than what is requested upon signing up for the Services.** In the event that we discover we have the Personal Information of a student without consent of a parent/legal guardian, or information in excess of what we request upon sign-up, we will permanently destroy that information as quickly as possible. If you believe a student may have provided us Personal Information without consent of a parent/legal guardian, or information in excess of what we request upon sign-up, please contact us at info@showbie.com.

(c) Students who have signed up with an access code provided by a school or teacher should be aware that their parent/legal guardian has access to all information within or associated with their Showbie account, including, but not limited to, messages between other students, teachers, and assignment grades.

(d) All students and teachers within a single course group in the password-protected portion of the Showbie site have the ability to view one another’s profiles, but visibility is limited to such information as their names, photographs and biographies. Students are unable to see the grades of other students, irrespective of whether or not they are members of the same course group on the site.

(e) The Showbie site allows students and teachers to interact, post information, assignments, grades and other similar information. This information will also form part of the Personal Information of students. However, Showbie acts as a Data Processor (as that term is defined below) of this Personal Information on behalf of the students’ school board, educational institution or teacher who has contracted with Showbie, and that school board, educational institution or teacher acts as the Data Controller (as that term is defined below) of that information.

#### 6\. Cookies

Showbie’s web applications use browser cookies to store session data for the currently signed in user. This allows our users to smoothly continue using Showbie after refreshing or closing their browser window. These cookies do not track user activity or transmit information to any third parties, and Showbie’s web applications cannot function fully without them. By signing up for Showbie you consent to the use of cookies as it relates to Showbie’s web applications.

#### 7\. Information of Others

By inputting any Personal Information into the Application (including the Personal Information of others), you consent to the use of that Personal Information within the Application, and you represent and warrant that you have obtained any permissions or authorizations for any Personal Information of others that you input or send through the Application. We do not use, collect or retain any of that information

#### 8\. Communication

You authorize us to communicate with you regarding our Services and your account. You authorize us to communicate with you via the internet and via the email address you have provided. You understand and accept the risk that data and information transmitted over the internet is susceptible to error or security breaches.

#### 9\. Information Use & Sharing

Showbie may use your Personal Information for the following purposes:

  * To provide and maintain our Application and Services
  * To notify you about changes to our Application and Services
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Application and Services when you choose to do so
  * To provide customer support
  * To gather analysis or valuable information so that we can improve our Application and Services
  * To monitor the usage of our Application and Services
  * To detect, prevent, and address technical issues

Except as disclosed in this Privacy Policy, we do not share, trade, sell or in any way disclose your Personal Information without your consent unless such a disclosure is: (a) required or permitted by law; (b) mandated by search warrant or court order; (c) warranted during investigation of the commission of an offence, a breach of a contract, or breach of a law or regulation; or (d) otherwise permitted under this policy or any other agreement you may have entered into with us. We may collect, aggregate and anonymize data for system monitoring, quality control, marketing and product improvement purposes, provided it does not collect, use or disclose any Personal Information of users. In some cases, we may collect, use and disclose Personal Information of administrative users or teachers for targeted marketing purposes provided it does not direct advertising to any student users, and provided that student Personal Information is not used or disclosed. In some cases, we may share Personal Information with our designated third-party service providers as required for account administration or otherwise in connection with providing the Services. We also may be required to disclose an individual’s Personal Information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

#### 10\. Dispute Resolution

In the event you have a question, complaint or dispute regarding your personal information or our personal information handling practices, contact us at the number(s) or email address(es) as displayed in the “Contact Us” section of our website. See also addendum 1.1 below in this regard.

#### 11\. Business Transfers

As a corporate entity, Showbie may elect to buy or sell assets. These transactions normally entail the transferring of user information, including Personal Information as a business asset. In such an event any acquirer of Showbie may continue to use personal information as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

#### 12. Retention of Data

Showbie will retain your Personal Information only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your Personal Information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our legal agreements and policies.

Showbie will also retain usage data for internal analysis purposes. Usage data is generally retained for a shorter period of time, except when this data is used to strengthen the security or to improve the functionality of our Services, or we are legally obligated to retain this data for longer time periods.

#### 13. Transfer of Data

Your information, including Personal Information, may be transferred and maintained on servers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

If you are located outside Canada or the United States and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Information, to Canada or the United States and process it there.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

Showbie will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your personal information will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other Personal Information.

#### 14. Security of Data

The security of your data is important to us, but no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially-acceptable means to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

#### 15. “Do Not Track” Signals

We do not support Do Not Track (“DNT”). Do Not Track is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked.

You can enable or disable Do Not Track by visiting the Preferences or Settings page of your web browser.

#### 16. Your Rights

Showbie aims to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete, or limit the use of your Personal Information.

Whenever made possible, you can update your Personal Information directly within your account settings section. If you are unable to change your Personal Information, please contact us to make the required changes.

If you wish to be informed what Personal Information we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us.

In certain circumstances, you have the right:

  * To access and receive a copy of the Personal Information we hold about you;
  * To rectify any Personal Information held about you that is inaccurate;
  * To request the deletion of Personal Information held about you;
  * To limit further processing, disclosure or use of your Personal Information.

If you wish to exercise these rights contact us using the contact details set out below.

Where we act as Data Processor and not Data Controller, we will refer your request to the applicable Data Controller, which, if you are a student, may be your teacher, school district, or your educational institution.

You also have the right to data portability for the information you provide to Showbie. You can request to obtain a copy of your Personal Information in a commonly used electronic format so that you can manage and move it.

We will ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.

#### 17. Service Providers

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service (“Service Providers”), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used. [Here](https://support.showbie.com/gdpr-compliance/data-management/who-showbie-shares-your-data-with) is a list of Service Providers Showbie currently uses.

These third parties have access to your Personal Information only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

In cases of onward transfer to third parties of Personal Information received, Showbie is potentially liable.

#### 18. Definitions

**Personal  Data  
**Personal Data means data about a living individual who can be identified from those data (or from those and other information either in our possession or likely to come into our possession), and any information about the individual associated with that information.

**Usage Data  
**Usage Data is data collected automatically either generated by the use of the Services or from the Service’s infrastructure itself (for example, the duration of a page visit).

**Cookies  
**Cookies are small pieces of data stored on a User’s device.

**Data Controller  
**Data Controller means a person who (either alone or jointly or in common with other persons) determines the purposes for which and the manner in which any Personal Data are, or are to be, processed.

For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are both a Data Controller and a Data Processor of your data.

**Data Processor (or Service Providers)  
**Data Processor (or Service Provider) means any person (other than an employee of the Data Controller) who processes the data on behalf of the Data Controller.

We may use the services of various Service Providers in order to process your data more effectively.

**Data Subject  
**Data Subject is any living individual who is the subject of Personal Data.

**User  
**The User is the individual using our Application or Services. The User corresponds to the Data Subject, who is the subject of Personal Data.

#### 19\. Changes

Changes to this Policy may be made from time to time by us, and the modified form of the Policy will take effect 10 days after posting on this page.

#### Contact Us

If You have questions about this Privacy Policy or wish to contact Showbie for any reason, please contact us at:

Privacy Officer  
Showbie Inc.,  
#403, 10113 104 Street NW,  
Edmonton, AB  
T5J 1A1

Email [privacy@showbie.com](mailto:privacy@showbie.com)

Last updated May 13, 2018

—

**ADDENDUM – 1.1 SHOWBIE INC. EU PRIVACY SHIELD AND SWISS-U.S. PRIVACY SHIELD CERTIFICATION INFORMATION**

EU-US PRIVACY SHIELD AND SWISS-U.S. CERTIFICATIONS

The following information aligns Showbie, Inc. Statement with the specific points required by the Privacy Shield self-certification process, and ensures Showbie, Inc.’s compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.

**Compliance  
**Showbie, Inc. complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of Personal Information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. Showbie has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles.  If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

**Complaints  
**In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Showbie commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your Personal Information.  EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield Policy should first contact Showbie at [privacy@showbie.com](mailto:privacy@showbie.com).

Showbie, Inc. has further committed to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning data transferred from the EU and Switzerland.

Please note that, under limited circumstances, a binding arbitration option may be available before a Privacy Shield panel.

Showbie, Inc is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

**Organization Information  
**Showbie US Inc  
304 S Jones Blvd  
Suite 1331  
Las Vegas, NV 89107, USA
